I found myself lost and alone on this journey
Though my heart wandered far and wide, I could move not an inch
But now I can depart for any distant land
Now that we've met on this road
Even the unfamiliar songs of travelers
Can spark nostalgia in me when I'm with you
If the world we dreamed of exists somewhere,
Then let's go search for it beyond the wind
Through chilling dawns,
Through arid noons,
Through shivering nights,
Let's go see what lies at the end
Wolf and a Lovers' Quarrel
W-Wolf?
If that's true, there's no mistaking their threat here.
"If you don't want your partner to be taken to the Church,
keep quiet until we've finished our business."
But there's no guarantee they won't turn her over to the Church anyway.
We've already invested heavily in Trenni silver by this point, too.
If we back off, we'll suffer huge losses.
We have to strike first!
Let's assume we rescue your partner and take her into asylum here.
If they report us and the Church searches this building,
we'll have no choice but to be as obedient sheep.
She can't hide as long as she's in this city.
We can leave town together.
You'll be caught unless you're extremely lucky.
If that happens, you might be taken to a different town and face persecution.
There would be nothing we could do in that case.
There's no way we can pay them off,
considering how much potential profit is at stake.
If only we had a card to play against them.
There is something.
My company could take the initiative and tell the Church that Medio Trading has your companion.
But if we do, you'll have a problem, right?
You might even give damaging testimony against us.
Without a doubt, I would.
The main point of the scheme
is to receive special rights from the king of Trenni, isn't it?
According to our reports,
the Royal Family is in dire financial straits.
I bet they are.
That's evident from the fact that they're planning to melt the currency in circulation
and decrease its silver content to issue a larger volume of coins.
If ten coins become thirteen, that's a profit of three coins.
They'll instantly raise funds,
but the country's reputation will fall under scrutiny and hurt them in the long term.
For the Trenni Royal Family to do this anyway proves that they're in financial trouble.
That's why, depending on how the negotiation goes,
mining rights, minting rights, tariff rights, and market administration rights are just a sample
of what the Royal Family may grant for our coins.
It's exactly as you say.
How does this sound?
Before Medio presses charges,
finish negotiating with the Royal Family,
and use the rights as a bargaining chip.
I'm sure her value is insignificant compared to those privileges.
Are you saying we should sell the rights?
Yes.
If they believe that they'd be better off buying your rights than crushing you,
Medio Trading will gladly pay the money.
They have a trump card that could send us to the stake.
No.
The last thing the Trenni royals want is trouble with the Church.
They wouldn't want the public to know that they dealt with
a trading company that was sent to the stake.
If we incur the wrath of the Church, they'll eventually turn
against the king, who'll be held responsible by association.
There's no way Medio Trading will prosecute,
since that would bring about the ire of the king.
I see.
But they'd still be reluctant to just back off without a fight.
Even though the only thing they could do is bring us down with them.
And that's where we offer the privileges in exchange for money and your companion.
Exactly.
In theory your plan makes perfect sense.
But there's a significant obstacle to its implementation.
As far as I can guess,
Medio Trading has yet to collect many silver coins.
What makes you say that?
If they had a significant amount of coins,
they would have headed to the Church the moment they captured Holo.
That they chose to forego that option and approach us here
is proof of their lack of confidence.
This plan is one that endeavors to exploit a king.
Medio will have had to keep their coin-gathering quiet.
Mr. Lawrence, what do you propose to do?
We retrieve Holo and I flee with her until you've finalized a deal.
That's preposterous!
Even if I'm unable to escape, I can buy you some time.
Collect as many coins as you can and begin the negotiations.
That's impossible!
In that case, do you plan to tell the Church about Holo?
You'll have to face my testimony if it comes to that.
With your help, I'll be able to evade capture for at least a day or two.
After all, my partner in crime is a wolf spirit.
If her only goal is escape,
and she uses her true abilities,
no human will be able to catch her.
Let me ask you a question.
How long will you need to assemble enough coins to command the king's attention?
If I dispatch someone by horse right now, he should reach Trenni Castle by dusk.
If the negotiations occur immediately,
he'll return by dawn tomorrow.
Right now? You don't even know how many coins you'll be able to collect, do you?
Guesswork has its place in negotiations.
We'll be fine as long as we secure the coins by the time they're due.
Can you reach a quick settlement with a king?
Any deal can be finalized promptly if we put our minds to it.
In that case, do you know where Holo is?
We are Milone Trading, you know.
Ambush of our employees and arson of our facilities
Hey.
are facts of daily life for us.
See you around.
We have contingencies for any emergency.
We do have one rival, though.
Is it the Church?
Correct.
They visit more towns and countries than we do,
and they're surprisingly well-prepared for crisis.
Should the Church launch a search in earnest, you must not run without thinking. Stay hidden in one place.
To tell you the truth, I would have liked to have known who
was backing Medio Trading before we started negotiations.
Then we would know where their funds were coming from
and might even be able to convince them to fund us instead.
Yes, it's not ideal.
I pray for your safety and success.
Your hopes will be met in full.
Oh, that's right.
The passwords are Pireon and Numai.
Two great gold coins, then.
It seemed auspicious.
Once I'm underground, I should touch the right-hand wall and move forward.
Correct?
Yes.
When you hit a wall, you've reached your destination.
Holo will be inside the storage room above.
Your retrieval of the hostage will occur as soon as the bell signals that the market is open.
If everything goes smoothly,
the hatch above the path will open and your partner will descend.
Should you hear the word "Rahhe,"
please wait for an escort to arrive.
If you hear Perouso, make your escape together along the planned route at once.
Rahhe and Perouso.
Prosperity and famine, huh?
Simple to remember, isn't it?
Very.
It's almost time.
You idiot! Watch out!
Sorry.
Go, quickly.
I didn't expect them to be so prepared.
I've heard tell of the Church digging graves as a pretense
to construct underground routes for spying on heretics and evading taxes.
This is it.
Follow me. We're moving.
I hope they don't have to resort to blades or clubs.
Damn.
Why am I trembling?
They're late.
Don't tell me...
Rahhe.
Numai.
Pireon.
Holo!
I'm supposed to carry this so people will think we're thieves, right?
Now, quick!
I can't come down if you're in the way.
Come on, hurry!
What are you staring at? This is yours.
Hold this and get going.
Yes?
Pireon.
Numai.
Looks like you made it safely.
Life in business is full of surprises.
Our guide is down there.
He'll remove the ladder and exit another way.
He'll then leave town once he informs his contacts about Medio's movements.
You're rather prepared.
Best of luck.
Thanks.
I'm relieved you're unharmed.
You're relieved to see I'm unharmed?
Yeah.
Say my name!
Holo... right?
Holo, the wise wolf!
R-Right.
I can remember every single person who ever shamed me in my life.
I must add a new name to that list.
Yours!
I don't...
Didn't I tell you to come and save me?
Y-Yeah.
I... I was so convinced that you came, and...
I feel angry just thinking about it!
Don't tell me you...
You're a male, aren't you? Shouldn't you have been at the forefront, fighting tooth and nail?
But you hid in a hole in the ground.
You let me make a fool of myself!
At least you're safe.
I'm glad you're all right.
I can't die as long as you hold on to the wheat.
Human males are easy prey since I'm so cute.
Yet, not one of my opponents were fit to be my mate.
They turned pale in fear as soon as I said,
"I'll sever your private parts if you so much as touch me."
Hey, now.
But...
That's when she appeared before me.
Can you guess who was among those who captured me?
Who?
Chloe.
The girl from Pasloei Village.
She apparently heard my name from Zheren.
Did you speak with her?
I thought you were simply a fairy tale.
Only for a moment.
"A wolf spirit lives within the village's wheat fields and determines the quality of the harvest on a whim."
I don't know how many years it's been since I settled down in that land.
Maybe as many as there are hairs on my tail.
I'm Holo, the wise wolf.
In order to provide the greatest harvest, I let the soil rest on occasion by producing a poor yield.
That was all part of managing the land.
Wheat would have grown better there than anywhere else.
It's true that the people of the village worshipped me as their god of harvest,
but not out of respect. It was more akin to a desire to control.
The person who reaps the last stalk of wheat is locked away.
Do you know what Chloe said to me?
She said she heard my name from Zheren, and it made her wonder if I was her Holo.
I... I...
I was happy, as shameful as that sounds.
However, she didn't stop there.
Gone are the days of having to court your favor.
There's no need to gnash our teeth at your fickle nature anymore.
I'll send you to the Church and bid farewell to all those dated traditions.
I... I...
I couldn't stand it!
Well, look at it a different way.
You'll have to leave the wheatfields in order to return to the north.
If they say you won't be missed, blind them with the dust cloud you leave.
It'll be a cleaner break that way.
You won't be leaving quietly, though.
I, I mean we, are merchants.
We profit, we triumph.
We'll laugh when we make money,
and cry when we don't have a cent.
And I think we'll end up laughing.
I feel better.
Well...
I haven't had a proper conversation in hundreds of years.
My emotions are far too fragile.
This is the second time I've cried in front of you,
but I would have done so even had you not been here.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Don't get the wrong idea?
Right.
I only brought you along to help me make money, anyway.
Our job is to run for as long as we can until Milone Trading negotiates a deal.
Having someone crying and carrying on in the middle of that is just a burden.
So regardless of who was crying in front of me, I'd...
Hey, that isn't fair.
Mm-hm. A female's privilege.
We've arrived.
Have you run out of things to say?
No.
The man behind Medio Trading is Count Ehrendott.
The merchant within the Count's manor in charge of
brokering wheat is responsible for collecting the silver coins.
Report this to Marlheit.
Consider it done.
It's true, then, that those who bring talk of profit are rather odd.
What, you mean my ears?
Looking at you two makes me want to live the life of a traveling merchant again.
I advise against it.
You'll end up stuck with someone like her.
Nothing wrong with that. The seat of a wagon is too big for one person anyway.
Surely I'm the unfortunate one,
to be picked up by the likes of you!
You're too clever by half.
That's what makes me so charming.
Well, that much is true.
I'm so happy you said that.
You really are an adorable boy.
Geez.
Next Episode: "Wolf and a Silent Farewell".